what do you do if you're that parent
thinking how do I get them moving I
don't want to push them too much right
you don't want to do that negative thing
and you have them get mad and so on and
so forth what's the right amount of
pushing what are some strategies well
number one just be more active yourself
that is always a good thing if your kid
is not active and you are not active
that is the easiest way kids will model
parents the kids will model community so
that said the second one is get them in
more environments where more kids and
more adults are moving if your community
your friends your family is on TV is on
phones and stuff all day they're going
to mimic that if they're just in
different environments they will mimic
that those are the two biggest steps you
can take you yourself as well as get
them in peer groups of kids who are more
active doesn't mean you can't let them
be friends with their kids who want to
play video games all day anymore but you
get the point put them around
environments where people are just more
active three and this is actually
something that has worked a lot with my
kid try different physical environments
this means play on the ground play in
the snow play in the water go into the
forest go into playgrounds go into gyms
go into courts get them in different
environments maybe they hate sport
courts but they love to play around in
the forest great maybe they are cold and
they hate the outdoors awesome try into
our pool whatever you can do to change
the physical environment maybe something
will resonate and hit with them there
that hasn't resonated in the sports that
you liked or the activities that your
spouse or your family liked another
thing similar idea try different
different movement modes if they don't
like running cuz they don't like playing
soccer they don't like playing football
or basketball try swimming try in the
water make them move their body
differently put them on a bike put them
on a board have them do skateboarding do
different things that are different not
just you moving your own body other
stuff may do it I can tell you right now
my daughter absolutely goes Bonkers over
swimming great I hate swimming hate it
personally don't like it at all she's
all into it fantastic I will take that
kid to the PO anytime she wants to go
and we can take her there right her
brother does like it at all awesome
whatever it takes different
environments similar concept try
different implements so bats different
rackets different balls long things
short things sticks
Flags whatever you're getting the point
right just try different exposures um
try another thing that's worked a lot
try different play Partners one thing
that happens with kids being so far
behind other kids if they're around
their peers only they tend to withdraw
and fall back if they're below them or
delayed so having them always compete
against the same kids who better than
them may not be your best option play
with them directly yourself a lot of
little kids don't want to play with
other kids for that reason but they will
play with you so you'll be the one to
play catch with them you'll be the one
to play the sports with them and not
only are you modeling the behavior but
they actually are more comfortable not
being good at something with you because
they don't have any reference point they
know Mom and Dad are better they just
know uncle's going to be better they
know Auntie's going to be better so they
don't have that negative experience
being the worst one in the group like
that if they have siblings same thing
maybe don't have them play with the
sibling if it's causing that negative
dynamic or cousin or whatever the case
is or the neighbor so on and so forth or
themselves maybe this the best scenario
is have them play with themselves more
practice by themselves rather than in
front of the other ones if that's
causing the problem finally try to make
things a different Ator between task
goals versus sport goals here's what I
mean maybe the kid has no interest in
sports but you can get them to build a
fort you can get them to do something
where hey we got to get all these rocks
into the water over there great they're
still going to be playing sports but
they don't care about winning they don't
care about points on the board but they
will do something like that maybe wasn't
the best example but hopefully you can
come up with your own example there
where you're getting them to do
different things that have a start a
stop here's what we're trying to do
we're going to accumulate points but the
points are different it has an outcome
that they like and it's not just
reward-based it is just actual intrinsic
reward we did our thing but the thing is
now not a sport or a score it is great
we build that cool deck awesome we put
that bridge across the water now we can
go all the way over you get the idea if
you enjoyed this clip you can watch the
full episode by clicking here